A Guide to the Home for Needy Confederate Women Records, 1862-1997
Library of Virginia
- III. Resident and application files, 1900-1997 (Box 14-27)
  - 1. Resident files, ca. 1917-1997 (Box 14-21)
    - Resident files: Bowles-Broaddus (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Resident files: Brooks-Burgess (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Resident files: Burroughs-Butler (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Resident files: Campbell-Canada (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Resident files: Cannon-Chapman (Box 15)
    - Resident files: Chappell-Christian (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Resident files: Clark-Cocke (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Resident files: Councill-Crist (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Resident files: Crump-Crute (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Resident files: Coffee-Cottingham (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Resident files: Dabney-Dawson (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Resident files: Deacon-Downer (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Resident files: Drake-Dunnavant (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Resident files: Early-Ely (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Resident files: Emmerson (Annie) (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Resident files: Emmerson (Mary)-Estes (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Resident files: Farrar-Ferneyhough (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Resident files: Ferrell-Fisher (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Resident files: Fleming-Frommer (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Resident files: Gallaher-Gaskins (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Resident files: Gay-Gray (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Resident files: Gregory-Guigon (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Resident files: Hackett-Harper (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Resident files: Harris-Haynes (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Resident files: Henley-Houston (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Resident files: Howard-Hutchings (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Resident files: Jefferson-Jordan (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Resident files: Joseph-Juhling (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Resident files: Kauffman-Kibler (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Resident files: Kidwell-Kline (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Resident files: Lacy-Leake (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Resident files: Lee-Littlepage (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Resident files: Long-Lytle (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Resident files: MacCorkle-McKinney (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Resident files: Marsh-Micou (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Resident files: Middleton-Monroe (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Resident files: Moon-Motley (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Resident files: Naylor-Neale (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Resident files: Neblett (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
    - Resident files: Nelson-Nunnally (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Resident files: Oliver-Owens (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Resident files: Palmore-Payne (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Resident files: Pendleton-Pierce (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Resident files: Poindexter-Proctor (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Resident files: Pruden-Purdy (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Resident files: Quarles-Redd (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Resident files: Rice-Rowelle (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Resident files: Roy-Royall (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Resident files: Samuel-Shaver (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Resident files: Shelton-Shepherd (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Resident files: Sinnott-Smith (Corrie) (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Resident files: Smith (Elizabeth)-Southard (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Resident files: Spain-Stickley (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Resident files: Story-Strong (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Resident files: Stuart-Sydnor (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Resident files: Taliaferro-Terrell (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Resident files: Thurman-Tillotson (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Resident files: Timberlake-Tiller (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Resident files: Tompkins (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Resident files: Torrence-Tyree (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Resident files: Vest-Ware (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Resident files: Waring-Watkins (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Resident files: Wayne-West (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Resident files: Wheeler-Wilkinson (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Resident files: Williams-Wiltse (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Resident files: Wiltshire-Wright (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Resident files: Yates (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Resident information notebook, ca. 1917-1951 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Resident information notebook, ca. 1932-1946 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Resident information notebook, ca. 1935-1968 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Resident information notebook, ca. 1957-1985 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Resident lists, 1936-1988 (intermittent) (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - 2. Application files, 1900-1979 (Box 22-27)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Abernathy-Anderson (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Anthony-Aylett (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Baber-Bass (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Batchelor-Bennett (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Berry-Blanton (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Blick-Boyce (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Brackett-Brinkley (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Britton-Brugh (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Buchanan-Buskill (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Campbell-Cecil (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Chamberlayne-Clanton (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Clark-Cole (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Coleman-Crumpton (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Dance-Davenport (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Davis-Denton (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Dickenson-Doggett (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Douglas-Dyson (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Eanes-Elliott (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Ellis-Ewers (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Faries-Fitzhugh (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Fleming-Furnival (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Gardner-Golt (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Goodacre-Guthrie (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Hackley-Hardy (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Harris-Heater (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Henley-Howard (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Howell-Hutchinson (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Irving-Jewell (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Johnson-Joyner (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Kay-Knight (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Lackay-Lehigh (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Lewis-Locke (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Locker-Lynn (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Applicants (did not enter): McAllister-McLearen (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Mahon-Massie (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Meagher-Moncure (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Monroe-Mullen (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Nance-Norris (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Oakes-Parrish (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Parsons-Pettit (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Pickett-Porter (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Potts-Putney (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Reed-Richardson (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Risk-Robey (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Robinson-Ryland (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Samuel-Shelton (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Shepherd-Sizer (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Smith-Snodgrass (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Sowell-Sydnor (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Taliaferro-Thomas (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Thorne-Toone (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Tuck-Toone (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Urquhart-Venable (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Waldron-Walton (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Ward-White (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Wicker-Winton (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Applicants (did not enter): Withers-Young (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Application Committee notebook, basic applicant info, ca. 1912-1932 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Application Committee notebook, basic applicant info, ca. 1932-1948 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Application Committee statistics, 1900-1909, and miscellaneous notes (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Applications from granddaughters, 1965-1974, A-D (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Applications from granddaughters, 1965-1974, E-L (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Applications from granddaughters, 1965-1974, M-R (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Applications from granddaughters, 1965-1974, S-W (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Confederate service record checks, 1966-1973 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, A (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, B (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, C (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, D (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, E-F (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, G (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, H (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, I-J (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, K-L (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, M (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, N-P (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, R (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, S-T (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, V-Y (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Letters requesting admission to the Home, unnamed candidates (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Out-of-state requests for applications, 1972-1979 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Waitings lists, 1949-1961 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Waitings lists, 1962-1965 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Waitings lists, 1966-1975 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Waitings lists, granddaughters, 1968-1972 (Box 27, Folder 15)
- IV. Financial papers, 1903-1990 (Box 28-41)
  Financial papers include yearly audit reports, 1916-1950 and 1964-1983 (some gaps), and annual and quarterly reports from the financial institutions handling the Home's endowment fund and investments, 1943-1990. Other items pertaining to stocks and bonds include Board resolutions ordering purchases or sales. Various ledgers, bills, receipts, statements, and reports to state agencies shed light on the fluctuating and often precarious financial situation of the Home. Also included are files on a handful of prominent donors.
  - Bank of Commerce and Trusts account activity, 1919-1920 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Budget estimates, 1938-1940 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1916-1920 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1921, 1924-1925 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1926-1930 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1931-1932 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1934-1935 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1936-1937 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1938-1939 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1940 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1941-1942 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1943-1944 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1945-1946 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1947-1948 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1949-1950 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1964-1966 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1967-1968 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1970-1971, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1975-1977 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1978-1979 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1980-1981 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - C.P.A. audit reports, 1982-1983 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Capitoline Investment Services--Contract and correspondence, 1973-1981 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Cash book, 1934-1940 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Cash book, 1974-1990 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Cash disbursements, 1979-1984 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Cash disbursements, 1985-1990 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - City of Richmond, taxation issues, 1904-1910, 1940-1941 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Disbursements, 1969-1975 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Donations--coal (Box 31, Folder 3-4)
  - Donations--Lists of persons solicited, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Donations--Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Donations--Virginia Department of Agriculture paperwork re: donated commodities, 1961-1964 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Donor lists, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Donors--Carnegie, Andrew, 1909-1910 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Donors--Cutting, R. Fulton, 1903-1904, 1910 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Donors--DuPont, Jessie Ball, and the Jessie Ball DuPont Religious, Charitable, and Educational Fund, 1943-1986 (Box 31, Folder 11-13)
  - Donors--Flagler, H.M., 1905, 1910-1911 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Donors--Huntington, Mrs. Collis P., 1903-1905 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Donors--Ryan, Thomas F., 1905, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Donors--Walke, Mrs. Frank Anthony, 1904-1909 (Box 31, Folder 17-18)
  - Drug bills, 1909-1911, 1920 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Electric bills, 1920, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Encumbrances, July 1942-May 1943 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Encumbrances, July 1944-April 1946 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1943-1944 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1944-1945 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1945-1946 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1946-1947 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1947-1948 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1948-1949 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1949-1950 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1950-1951 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1951-1952 (partial) (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1952-1953 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1953-1954 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1955-1956 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1956-1957 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1957-1958 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1958-1959 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1959-1960 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1960-1961 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1961-1962 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1963-1964 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1964-1965 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1965-1966 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1966-1967 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1967-1968 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1968-1969 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1969-1970 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1971-1972 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1972-1973 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1974-1975 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, 1975-1976 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, June 1988-March 1989 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Endowment fund/investment reports, March 1989-March 1990 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Final balance before closing the books, 1951-1967 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Financial information needed for audit, period ending June 1989 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Financial information needed for audit, period ending February 1990 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Financial journal, 1972-1990 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Financial statements, 1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Financial statements, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - First and Merchants National Bank, correspondence, 1938-1944, 1963, 1971-1973 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Gas and water bills, 1910-1911, 1920 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Grocery bills, 1905-1920, 1945, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Hardware bills, 1910 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Household goods and furnishing bills, 1909-1911, 1920 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Ice bills, 1909-1910, 1920 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Interest payments to residents, 1974-1984, 1988-1989 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Internal Revenue Service. Home application for tax exemption, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Internal Revenue Service. Notification concerning foundation status, 1970-1982 (intermittent) (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Internal Revenue Service. Tax withholding documents, 1943-1951 (Box 36, Folder 12-13)
  - Laundry bills, 1909-1911, 1920 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Ledger, 1926 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Ledger, 1934-1948 (Box 36, Folder 16-17)
  - Ledger, 1938-1947 (Box 37, Folder 1-4)
  - Ledger, 1974-1990 (bulk 1987-1990) (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous expenditures (Box 37, Folder 6-7)
  - Operating fund account activity, 1952-1965 (intermittent) (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Receipts and disbursements, 1906 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Receipts and disbursements, 1907-1909 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Receipts and disbursements, November-December 1913 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Receipts and disbursements, 1919 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Receipts and disbursements, 1923, 1931 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Shipping and freight bills, 1904-1911, 1939, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - State appropriations legislation, 1940, 1942 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - State appropriations matters, 1916-1986 (Box 37, Folder 16-17)
  - Statements of assets, 1938, 1942 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - State Planters Bank and Trust Co., agency agreement, 1956 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - State Planters Bank and Trust Co., correspondence, 1939-1964 (intermittent) (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - State Planters Bank and Trust Co., custodian agreement, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - State Planters Bank and Trust Co., deposit slips, 1936-1954 (intermittent) (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1930-1937 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1938-1939 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1940 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1945-1946 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1947-1948 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1949 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1950 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1951 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1953 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1954 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1955 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1957-1959 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1960, 1963-1964 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Stocks and bonds, 1970-1971 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Telephone bills, 1920 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - United Virginia Bank correspondence, 1969-1970, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Virginia. Auditor of Public Accounts, financial statements to, 1934-1940 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Virginia. Auditor of Public Accounts, financial statements to, 1941-1948 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Virginia. Auditor of Public Accounts. Reports on audits, 1941, 1943 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Virginia. Auditor of Public Accounts. Reports on audits, 1931-1933, 1937, 1939 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Virginia. Comptroller, expense reports to, 1948-1964 (intermittent) (Box 39, Folder 17)
    See also Series II. Board meetings--Minutes, reports, etc. for the years 1969-1990. The treasurer's reports in these files contain the same type of information.
  - Virginia. Comptroller. Statements of Expenditure by Activities and Objects, July 1936-June 1937 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Virginia. Comptroller. Statements of Invoices Paid, July 1936-June 1937 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Virginia. Comptroller. Statements of Invoices Paid, July 1938-December 1938 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Virginia. Comptroller. Statements of Invoices Paid, January-June 1939 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Virginia. Comptroller. Statements of Invoices Paid, July 1942-July 1943 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Virginia. Comptroller. Statements of Invoices Paid, July 1943-July 1944 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Virginia. Comptroller. Statements of Invoices Paid, July 1944-July 1945 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Virginia. Comptroller. Statements of Invoices Paid, July 1945-July 1946 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Trust Company, 1931-1933 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Trust Company, 1936-1938 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Voucher, 1935 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Voucher register, 1934-1946 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    Note that, because of its size, this volume is stored in an earlier box, out of sequence with the surrounding files.
  - Vouchers, January-April 1942 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Vouchers, April-June 1942 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Vouchers, July-September 1942 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Vouchers, October 1942-July 1943 (1-2 of 4) (Box 40, Folder 15-16)
  - Vouchers, October 1942-July 1943 (3-4 of 4) (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
- V. Property files, 1900-1989 (Box 41-43)
  Deeds, tax bills, ledgers, and communications with property managers document the various real estate holdings of the Home for Needy Confederate Women, including the buildings housing the Home itself and others acquired through residents. As-built drawings for a major 1986 roof renovation are among the papers relating to the construction and maintenance of the Sheppard Street residence. Many of the individual resident files in Series III also contain papers relating to properties turned over to the Home by the women. Also of note are the General Assembly's deed, 1926, and revised deed, 1977, controlling the Home's occupancy of the Sheppard Street site.
  - 3 E. Grace Street residence--Deeds, maintenance, etc. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - 301 N. Sheppard Street residence--Construction and maintenance (Box 41, Folder 4-8)
  - A.L. Adamson and Co. (management of 309 W. 27th Street property) (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - B.A. Cephas (management of 301 E. Clay Street Property) (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Charles A. Rose Co. (management of Parkwood Avenue properties), 1933-1937 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - City of Norfolk v. Home for Needy Confederate Women (re: unpaid property taxes), 1951 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Disaster plan draft (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1935 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1936 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1937 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1938 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1939 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1940 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1941 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1942 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1943 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1944 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1945 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1946 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1947-1949 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Elam and Funsten (various properties), 1950-1954 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Fire at 301 N. Sheppard St., 1974 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Fire safety inspections, 1971-1989 (intermittent) (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - General Assembly. Provision of site for Home, 1926 (Box 43, Folder 1)